NICHOLAS P. SOKOLOWSKI

5 757-319-2439

☑ nicksokolowski7@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/nick-sokolowski Qgithub.com/soko77788

SUMMARY

Highly motivated programmer with strong knowledge of application development tools such as VS Code to create responsive applications with Languages including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript as well as integrate databases with Postgres and build servers using Express; Commended by professors for quick learning, attention to detail, grasp of multiple technologies, and programming abilities; Known as a team-player.

SKILLS

- HTML
- **CSS**
- JavaScript
- API's
- Python 3

- Bootstrap
- Node.JS/Packages
- **Express Servers**
- Postgres SQL (Mysql)
- Git and Github

- Handlebars Templating
- MongoDB
- React
- **MERN Stack**
- Command Line

STRENGTHS

✓ Critical Thinking &. **Problem Solving**

✓ Precision & Attention to Detail ✓ Collaboration & Teamwork

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

edX Full Stack Developer Certificate – University of WI–Madison	2024
Free Code Camp Responsive Web Design Certification	2023-2024
Codecademy Pro Courses – HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python 3	2023-2024
ACSM Personal Training Certification – American College of Sports Medicine	2020
Physical Education (for licensure) – University of WI–Whitewater	2007-2011

WORK HISTORY

Personal Fitness Trainer

Wisconsin Athletic Club – Greenfield, WI Xperience Fitness – Hales Corners, WI Soko-ology (self-employed)

August 2023 – Present February 2021 – July 2023 June 2019 – August 2023

- Earned "Top 5 Trainers" recognition consistently out of over 100 trainers
- Regularly generated \$8k-\$10k in monthly revenue through package and supplement sales
- Listened to client's physical needs and goals to become acquainted with any limitations
- Observed and analyzed client's abilities to assess level of exercises to recommend
- Designed comprehensive exercise programs including strength-training, cardio and stretching
- Demonstrated exercise form, techniques, and proper use of equipment and taught safety tips
- Provided written documentation of exercise program with short-term and long-term goals
- Recorded progress and altered program as needed
- Identified nutritional and lifestyle changes to enhance fitness program
- Introduced additional resources (websites, podcasts, videos) regarding overall wellness

Commercial Furniture Assembly

Integra Seating – Walworth, WI

May 2013 – March 2020

- Consistently met and exceeded all quotas and timelines, leading to several promotions
- Performed furniture assembly functions of different components, cross-training into foam adhesion, mill assembly, finishing, and final assembly with great detailing and accuracy.